A Guide to the Papers of Ann Beattie
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Ann Beattie 1988-1989
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10414-w
This collection consists of 30 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 1992 April 16.
Scope and Content Information
Papers contain typescripts of Picturing Will, and short stories "Distant music," "Nineteen years," "The sweetest song," "Windy day at the resevoir," and "The working girl," together with a letter from Robert Shapard and one from Rust Hills on editorial matters.
With these are manuscripts or proofs of books by other authors: As much as I know by Susan Thames, Extraordinary people by Paul Gervais, Getting Jesus in the mood by Anne Brashler, The phoenix tree and other stories by Satoko Kizaki, Plain grief by Maxine Chernoff, Such a lovely couple by Linda Yellin, Under the light by Sam Michel, After moondog by Jane Shapiro, The brothers K by David James Duncan, And the desert shall blossom by Phyllis Barber.
Also The elephant by Richard Rayner, The evening star by Larry McMurtry, Final heat by Philip Lee Williams, The late night muse by Better Pesetsky, The patron saint of liars by Ann Patchett, Secret anniversaries by Scott Spencer, The sun maiden by Erika Taylor, Touching the rock: an experience of blindness by John M. Hull, and The tree of knowledge by Eva Figes.
Contents List
- Manuscripts by Ann Beattie
  - "Distant Music" by Ann Beattie in Secrets and Surprisesn.d., TMs (Box 1)
    with autograph corrections
  - "Ninteen Years" by Ann Beattie 1989 Mar 3, TMsS & TLS (Box 1)
    with a letter from Robert Shapard of Manoa discussing editing changes in the story for publication
  - Picturing Will by Ann Beattie [1989?], TMs (EC) (Box 1)
    Electrostatic Copy of the Typescript with Corrections and Changes (2 folders)
  - Picturing Will by Ann Beattie [1989?], TMs (Box 1)
    Part I, Uncorrected Typescript
  - "The Sweetest Songs" by Ann Beattie n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - Untitled Short Story by Ann Beattie n.d., TMs (EC) (Box 1)
    Electrostatic Copy of the Typescript and its Corrections and Changes
  - "Windy Day at the Reservoir" by Ann Beattie n.y. Jun 28, TMs (EC) & ALS (Box 1)
    with a letter from Rust Hills at Esquire discussing the story
  - "The Working Girl" by Ann Beattie in n.d., TMs (EC) (Box 1)
- Foldered Manuscripts by Other Authors
  - As Much As I Know by Susan Thames 1991, TMs (EC) (Box 1)
  - Extraordinary People by Paul Gervais n.d., TMs (EC) (Box 1)
    (2 folders)
  - Getting Jesus in the Mood by Anne Brashler 1991, page proof (Box 2)
  - The Phoenix Tree and Other Stories by Satoko Kizaki, translated by Carol A. Flath 1990, TMs (Box 2)
    with a letter from Stephanie Dinkins (2 folders)
  - Plain Grief by Maxine Chernoff n.d., TMs (EC) (Box 2)
  - "Sole Custody" in The Atlantic by Lynna Williams 1991 Sep, printed (Box 2)
  - 1991, TMs (Box 2)
    with a letter from Jamie Raab
  - Under the Light by Sam Michel n.d., Page Proof (EC) (Box 2)
- Bound Manuscripts by Other Authors
  - After Moondog by Jane Shapiro 1992, page proof (Box 3)
  - The Brothers K by David James Duncan 1992, page proof (Box 3)
  - And the Desert Shall Blossom by Phyllis Barber 1991, TMs (Box 3)
  - The Elephant by Richard Rayner 1991, page proof (Box 3)
  - The Evening Star by Larry McMurtry 1992, page proof (Box 3)
  - Final Heat by Philip Lee Williams 1992, page proof (Box 3)
  - The Late Night Muse by Bette Pesetsky 1991, page proof (Box 3)
  - The Patron Saint of Liars by Ann Patchett 1992, page proof (Box 3)
  - Secret Anniversaries by Scott Spencer 1990, page proof (Box 4)
  - The Sun Maiden by Erika Taylor 1991, page proof (Box 4)
  - Touching the Rock An Experience of Blindness by John M. Hull 1990, page proof (Box 4)
  - The Tree of Knowledge by Eva Figes 1991, page proof (Box 4)